<?xml version="1.0" encoding="US-ASCII"?>
<!DOCTYPE rfc SYSTEM "rfc2629.dtd" [
        <!ENTITY RFC2119 SYSTEM "http://xml.resource.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.2119.xml">
        <!ENTITY RFC8174 SYSTEM "http://xml.resource.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.8174.xml">
        <!ENTITY IANA_RM_CODE_BGP_PDU "1">
        <!ENTITY IANA_RM_CODE_GROUP "2">
        <!ENTITY IANA_RM_CODE_VRF "3">
        <!ENTITY IANA_RM_CODE_SP "4">
        ]>

<?xml-stylesheet type='text/xsl' href='rfc2629.xslt' ?>
<?rfc strict="yes" ?>
<?rfc toc="yes"?>
<?rfc tocdepth="4"?>
<?rfc symrefs="yes"?>
<?rfc sortrefs="yes" ?>
<?rfc compact="yes" ?>
<?rfc subcompact="no" ?>

<rfc category="std" docName="draft-ietf-grow-bmp-tlv-17"
     ipr="trust200902" submissionType="IETF"
     updates="7854">

    <front>
        <title abbrev="BMP TLV">
	    BMP v4: TLV Support for BGP Monitoring Prtoocol (BMP) Route Monitoring and Peer Down Messages
	</title>

        <author fullname="Paolo Lucente" initials="P" surname="Lucente">
            <organization>NTT</organization>
            <address>
                <postal>
                    <street>Veemweg 23</street>
                    <city>Barneveld</city>
                    <code>3771</code>
                    <region>MT</region>
                    <country>NL</country>
                </postal>
                <email>paolo@ntt.net</email>
            </address>
        </author>
        <author fullname="Yunan Gu" initials="Y" surname="Gu">
            <organization>Huawei</organization>
            <address>
                <postal>
                    <street>Huawei Bld., No.156 Beiqing Rd.</street>
                    <city>Beijing</city>
                    <code>100095</code>
                    <region></region>
                    <country>China</country>
                </postal>
                <email>guyunan@huawei.com</email>
            </address>
        </author>

        <date year="2025"/>

        <area>General</area>

        <workgroup>Global Routing Operations</workgroup>
        <keyword>BGP</keyword>
        <keyword>BMP</keyword>
        <keyword>tlv</keyword>

        <abstract>
            <t>
		Most of the BGP Monitoring Protocol (BMP) message types make provision
		for data in Type, Length, Value (TLV) format. However, Route Monitoring
		messages (which provide a snapshot of the monitored Routing Information
		Base) and Peer Down messages (which indicate that a peering session was
		terminated) do not. Supporting (optional) data in TLV format across
		all BMP message types provides consistent and extensible structures
		that would be useful among the various use-cases where conveying
		additional data  to a monitoring station is required. This document updates
		<xref target="RFC7854">RFC 7854</xref> to support TLV data in all message
		types.
            </t>
        </abstract>
    </front>

    <middle>
        <section title="Introduction" anchor="Introduction">
            <t>
		The BGP Monitoring Protocol (BMP) version 3 is defined in <xref target="RFC7854">RFC 7854</xref>.
	    </t>

            <t>
		The Route Monitoring message consists of:
		<list style="symbols">
			<t>Common Header</t>
			<t>Per-Peer Header</t>
			<t>BGP Update PDU</t>
		</list>
	    </t>

	    <t>
		The Peer Down Notification message consists of:
		<list style="symbols">
			<t>Common Header</t>
			<t>Per-Peer Header</t>
			<t>Reason</t>
			<t>Data (only if Reason code is 1, 2 or 3)</t>
			<t>TLV (only if Reason code is 6)</t>
		</list>
	   </t>

           <t>
		This means that both Route Monitoring and Peer Down messages have
		a non-extensible format (except for the specific case of Peer Down
		Reason Code 6 as specified in <xref section="5.3" sectionFormat="of"
		target="RFC9069"/>). In the Route Monitoring case, this prevents
		the transmission of parsing characteristics of transported NLRIs
		(e.g. ADD-PATH, Multi Labels, etc.), RIB status of a path (e.g.
		primary, backup, unused, etc.) or of vendor-specific data. In the
		Peer Down case, this prevents matching with TLVs previously sent
		with the Peer Up message. This document:
		<list style="symbols">
			<t>Bumps the BMP version for all message types defined in
			   <xref target="RFC7854">RFC 7854</xref> for backward compatibility</t>
			<t>Changes the structure of Route Monitoring message type so that the BGP
			   Update PDU is enclosed in a TLV. The BGP Message PDU TLV is mandatory
			   to be included</t>
			<t>Allows all defined BMP message types to make provision for optional
			   TLV data.</t>
		</list>
            </t>
        </section>

        <section title="Terminology">
            <t>
		The key words "MUST", "MUST NOT", "REQUIRED", "SHALL", "SHALL
		NOT", "SHOULD", "SHOULD NOT", "RECOMMENDED", "NOT RECOMMENDED",
		"MAY", and "OPTIONAL" in this document are to be interpreted as
		described in BCP 14 <xref target="RFC2119">RFC 2119</xref>
		<xref target="RFC8174">RFC 8174</xref> when, and only when, they
		appear in all capitals, as shown here.
            </t>
	    <t>
		The document uses the terms defined in <xref target="RFC7854">RFC 7854</xref>.
            </t>
        </section>

	<section title="Message version">
	    <t>
		For an exporter to flag a receiver that it does comply with this
		specification, the Version field of the BMP Common header, documented
		in <xref target="RFC7854">Section 4.4 of</xref>, MUST be set to 4. This
		applies to every BMP message type.	
	    </t>
	    <t>
		If a BMP station does not support the version indicated in the message,
		it SHOULD close the session and take the procedures described in
		<xref target="ErrHdl">Error Handling</xref>
	    </t>
	</section>

	<section title="TLV Encoding">
	    <t>
		The TLV data type (Information TLV) is defined in <xref target="RFC7854">
		Section 4.4 of</xref> for the Initiation and Peer Up message types. A
		TLV object consists of:
	    </t>
	    <t>
		<list style="symbols">
		    <t>
			2 octets of TLV Type,
		    </t>
		    <t>
			2 octets of TLV Length, and
		    </t>
		    <t>
			0 or more octets of TLV Value.
		    </t>
		</list>
	    </t>

	    <figure anchor="BMP-TLV-header" align="center">
	    	<artwork align="center">
	    	    <![CDATA[
  0 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 0 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 0 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 0 1
  +-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+
  |        Type (2 octets)        |     Length (2 octets)         |
  +-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+
  ~                      Value (variable)                         ~
  +-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+
	    	    ]]>
	    	</artwork>
	    </figure>

	    <t>
		TLVs SHOULD be sorted by the sender by their type. Multiple
		TLVs of the same type can be repeated as part of the same message;
		it is left to the specific use-cases whether all, any, the
		first or the last TLV should be considered as well as whether
		ordering matters and repeating is allowed.
	    </t>

	    <t>
	        Route Monitoring messages may require per-NLRI TLVs. That is, there may
		be a need to map TLVs to NLRIs contained in the BGP Update message, for
		example, to express additional characteristics of a specific NLRI. For
		this purpose, TLVs enclosed in a Route Monitoring message MUST be
		indexed, with the index starting at one (1) to refer to the first NLRI.
		Index zero (0) specifies that a TLV does apply to all NLRIs contained in
		the BGP Update message. The Index field is 2-byte long of which the
		top-most bit, G-bit, is used to flag a Group Index (more in <xref
		target="GroupTLVinRM"/>).
		TLVs of the same type and with the same index can be repeated
		as part of the same message, unless specified otherwise by the definition
		of the specific TLV. Indexed TLVs are encoded as in the following figure:
	    </t>

	    <figure anchor="BMP-indexed-TLV-header" align="center">
	    	<artwork align="center">
	    	    <![CDATA[
  0 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 0 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 0 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 0 1
  +-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+
  |        Type (2 octets)        |     Length (2 octets)         |
  +-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+
  |G|      Index (15 bits)        |
  +-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+
  ~                      Value (variable)                         ~
  +-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+
	    	    ]]>
	    	</artwork>
	    </figure>

	    <t>
		Indexed TLVs SHOULD be sorted by the sender by their type and
		index value. The reported length in indexed TLVs refers to the
		total encoded TLV value (ie. with the length of the index field
		excluded).
	    </t>

	    <t>
		A monitoring station can properly match indexed TLVs to the
		corresponding NLRI only if - or as long as - NLRIs are decoded
		successfully. In case of any parsing or error condition that
		prevents full decoding of the BGP PDU, the station MUST stop
		matching indexed TLVs to NLRIs.
	    </t>

	    <t>
	        Of the BMP message types defined so far, indexed TLVs apply only to
		Route Monitoring messages. For example, they do not apply to Route
		Mirroring messages because a sender may not be aware of the payload
		of the transported BGP Update message.
	    </t>
	</section>

        <section title="BMP Message Format">
            <section title="Common Header" anchor="CommonHeader">
                <t>
			While the structure of the Common header remains unaltered,
			the following two definitions are changed compared to
			<xref section="4.1" sectionFormat="of" target="RFC7854"/>:
		     
		    <list style="symbols">
			<t>
				Version: Indicates the BMP version. This is set
				to '4' for all message types defined in
				<xref target="RFC7854">RFC 7854</xref>.
			</t>
			<t>
				Message Length: Total length of the message in
				bytes (including headers, encapsulated BGP Message
				PDU TLV and optional TLV data).
			</t>
		    </list> 
                </t>
            </section>
	    <section title="TLV Data in Route Monitoring" anchor="TLVinRM">
		<t>
			For consistency with the Route Mirroring type defined in <xref
			section="4.7" sectionFormat="of" target="RFC7854"/>, this document
			extends the encoding of the Route Monitoring message type where the
		    	Per-peer header is followed by mandatory and optional TLVs.  
		</t>
		<t>
		    	The BGP Update PDU (<xref section="4.3" sectionFormat="of"
			target="RFC4271"/>) is encoded itself as part of a BGP Message TLV
			with code point &IANA_RM_CODE_BGP_PDU; and index set to zero. A Route
			Monitoring message MUST contain one BGP Message TLV which may be
			preceded or followed by other optional TLV data.
		</t>
		<t>
		    	Corollary, the BGP Update PDU is not encoded as part of the message
			as it was the case for BMPv3 (<xref target="RFC7854">RFC 7854</xref>)
			but it is rather enclosed in a TLV.
		</t>
	    <section title="Group TLV" anchor="GroupTLVinRM">
		<t>
		    In a Route Monitoring message where a BGP Update PDU carries N
		    NLRIs, indexed TLVs do allow to handle the cases of 1:1 and N:1
		    relationship among TLVs and NLRIs (ie. one TLV applies to one
		    NLRI, N TLVs apply to one same NLRI). The cases of 1:N and M:N
		    relationships (i.e., one TLV applies to N NLRIs and M TLVs apply
		    to N NLRIs) can benefit by a form of grouping. For that purpose,
		    a Group TLV is defined with the aim to limit both verbosity and
		    repetitions.
		</t>
		<t>
		    The Group TLV value MUST contain:
		    <list style="symbols">
		    <t>A 2-byte Group Index where the top-most bit (G-bit) MUST 
		    be set to one (1). The full 2-byte value, that is including the
		    G-bit, MUST be unique to the message</t>
		    <t>Two or more 2-byte NLRI indexes whose values MUST be less
		    or equal to the amount of NLRIs packed in the BGP Update PDU.</t>
		    </list>
		    An NLRI index can be listed as part of multiple Group TLVs within
		    the same message. NLRI indexes within a Group TLV SHOULD be sorted
		    by the sender. A Group Index MUST NOT reference an NLRI index 0.
		    A Group TLV MUST NOT include its own or another Group Index.
		    Multiple non-Group TLVs MAY point to the same Group Index, i.e.,
		    a group can be reused within the same Route Monitoring message.
		</t>
		<t>
		    The Group TLV type is &IANA_RM_CODE_GROUP;. It is RECOMMENDED 
		    that this TLV is encoded first in order to ease parsing of the
            	    Route Monitoring message at the BMP station side.
		</t>
	    </section>
	    <section title="VRF/Table Name TLV" anchor="VrfTLVinRM">
		<t>
		    The Information field contains a UTF-8 string whose value MUST
		    be equal to the value of the VRF or table name (i.e., RD instance
		    name) being conveyed. The string size MUST be within the range
		    of 1 to 255 bytes. This is in line with <xref section="5.2.1"
		    sectionFormat="of" target="RFC9069"/>.
		</t>
		<t>
		    The VRF/Table Name TLV type is &IANA_RM_CODE_VRF;
		</t>
	    </section>
	    <section title="Stateless Parsing TLV" anchor="SpTLVinRM">
		<t>
		    Stateless parsing helps scaling the amount of Route Monitoring
		    messages that can be processed at collection time, avoiding to
		    have to correlate them to BGP capabilities received as part of
		    the Peer Up message, for example.
		</t>
		<t>
		    Some BGP capabilities are not per AFI/SAFI, like 4-byte ASN
		    <xref target="RFC6793">RFC 6793</xref>, and hence these can
		    potentially be part of the <xref target="IANA-BPPF">BMP Peer
		    flags</xref> of a Route Monitoring message. Those that are,
		    instead, per AFI/SAFI require finer granularity and hence the
		    need to use an indexed TLV.
		</t>
		<t>
		    The Stateless Parsing TLV type is &IANA_RM_CODE_SP; and its
		    Value is organized as follows:

		    <list style="symbols">
		    <t>Capability Type, 1 byte</t>
		    <t>Capability Value, variable length</t>
		    </list>
		</t>
		<t>
		    The Capability Type field encodes a value from the <xref
		    target="IANA-BCC">BGP Capabilities Codes</xref> registry defined 
		    by <xref target="RFC5492">RFC 5492</xref>.
		</t>
		<t>
		    The Capability Value encodes the BGP capability exactly as it
		    is encoded in the BGP Open of the session. For example, an
		    ADD-PATH capability, as defined by <xref target="RFC7911">RFC
		    7911</xref>, for IP/Unicast with value Send/Receive would be
		    encoded in the Capability Value as: 
		</t>  
		<t>
		    <list style="symbols">
		    <t>AFI, 2 bytes, value=1</t>
		    <t>SAFI, 1 byte, value=1</t>
	            <t>Value, 1 byte, value=3</t>
		    </list>
		</t>
		<t>
		    The index of the Stateless Parsing TLV MUST be set to zero. 
		</t>
		<t>
		    If no Stateless Parsing TLV is present in a Route Monitoring
		    message, the receiver MUST fall back to use capabilities present
		    in the BGP Open PDU contained in the relevant BMP Peer Up message
		    in order to properly parse BGP Update PDUs. Each BGP capability  
		    is to be encoded in a separate Stateless Parsing TLV.
		</t>
		<t>
		    It is RECOMMENDED that the Stateless Parsing TLV is encoded
		    preceding the BGP Message TLV in order to ease parsing of the
		    Route Monitoring message at the BMP station side.
		</t>
	    </section>
        </section>
	    <section title="TLV Data in Peer Down" anchor="TLVinPD">
		<t>
		    The Peer Down Notification message type (<xref section="4.9"
		    sectionFormat="of" target="RFC7854"/>) is extended following
		    a consistent approach with the Peer Up type (<xref section="4.10"
		    sectionFormat="of" target="RFC7854"/>). That is, the message
		    is extended so that optional TLVs are placed at the end of
		    the message.
		</t>
		<t>
		    This means for Reason codes 1 or 3, a BGP Notification
		    PDU follows; the PDU MAY be further followed by TLV data. 
		    For Reason code 2, a 2-byte field follows to provide
		    additional Finite State Machine (FSM) info; this field MAY
		    be followed by TLV data. For all other Reason codes, TLV
		    data MAY follow the Reason field.
		</t>
	    </section>
	    <section title="TLV Data in Other BMP Messages" anchor="TLVinOther">
		<t>
		    All other message types defined in <xref target="RFC7854">RFC7854</xref>
		    do already provision for TLV data. It is RECOMMENDED that
		    all future defined BMP message types will also provide for
		    optional TLV data following a consistency model for encoding
		    with existing message types.
		</t>
	    </section>
        </section>

        <section title="Error Handling" anchor="ErrHdl">
	    <t>
		<xref target="RFC8654">RFC8654</xref> permits BGP Update and other
		messages to grow to a length of 65535 octets. This may cause a BMP
		PDU that attempts to encapsulate such long messages to overflow.
	    </t>
	    <t>
		A BMP exporter and a BMP station may not support the same version
		of the protocol; being BMP uni-directional, with data flowing only
		from the exporter to the station, the station SHOULD close the BMP
		session and log the condition as a warning; the exporter SHOULD
		retry to connect with a non-aggressitve timer.
	    </t>
	    <t>
 		A BMP station may not support some of the TLVs encoded by the
		exporter; the station MUST ignore unsupported TLV types; additionally,
		in case of indexed TLVs, if the index is invalid (i.e. out of bounds),
		the TLV MUST be ignored. The station SHOULD log the condition as a
		warning.  
	    </t>
        </section>

        <section title="Security Considerations">
            <t>
                It is not believed that this document adds any additional security
		considerations compared to <xref target="RFC7854">RFC7854</xref>.
            </t>
        </section>

        <section title="Operational Considerations">
            <t>
                In Route Monitoring messages, the number of TLVs can be bound to
		the amount of NLRIs carried in the BGP Update message. This may
		degrade the packing of information in such messages and have
		specific impacts on the memory and CPU used in a BMP implementation.
		As a result of that it should always be possible to disable such
		features to mitigate their impact.
            </t>
        </section>

        <section title="IANA Considerations">
            <t>
		This document requests IANA to rename of the "Peer Up TLVs" registry defined by
		<xref target="RFC9736">BMP Peer Up Message Namespace</xref> into "Peer Up and
		Peer Down TLVs" and the definition of one new registry "BMP Route Monitoring
		TLVs". The new "BMP Route Monitoring TLVs" registry is seeded with the following
		new TLV types (<xref target="TLVinRM"/>):

		<list style="symbols">
		    <t>
			Type = &IANA_RM_CODE_BGP_PDU;: Support for BGP Message TLV. The value
			field is defined in <xref target="TLVinRM"/>
		    </t>
		    <t>
			Type = &IANA_RM_CODE_GROUP;: Support for grouping of TLVs. The value
			field is defined in <xref target="GroupTLVinRM"/>. The recommended
			value for this TLV is 0.
		    </t>
		    <t>
			Type = &IANA_RM_CODE_VRF;: Support for VRF/Table Name TLV. The value
			field is defined in <xref target="VrfTLVinRM"/>
		    </t>
		    <t>
			Type = &IANA_RM_CODE_SP;: Support for Stateless Parsing TLV. The value
			field is defined in <xref target="SpTLVinRM"/>. The recommended value
			for this TLV is 1.
		    </t>
		</list>
            </t>
        </section>

    </middle>

    <back>

        <references title="Normative References">
		&RFC2119;
		&RFC8174;

		<?rfc include="reference.RFC.4271.xml"?>
		<?rfc include="reference.RFC.7854.xml"?>
		<?rfc include="reference.RFC.8654.xml"?>
		<?rfc include="reference.RFC.9069.xml"?>
		<?rfc include="reference.RFC.9736.xml"?>
        </references>
	<references title="Informative References">
                <?rfc include="reference.RFC.5492.xml"?>
		<?rfc include="reference.RFC.6793.xml"?>
		<?rfc include="reference.RFC.7911.xml"?>
                <reference anchor="IANA-BCC" target="https://www.iana.org/assignments/capability-codes/">
                        <front>
                                <title>
                                        Capabilities Codes
                                </title>
                                <author>
                                        <organization>
                                                IANA
                                        </organization>
                                </author>
                                <date year="2025" />
                        </front>
                </reference>
                <reference anchor="IANA-BPPF" target="https://www.iana.org/assignments/bmp-parameters/bmp-parameters.xhtml#peer-flags">
                        <front>
                                <title>
                                        BMP Peer Flags
                                </title>
                                <author>
                                        <organization>
                                                IANA
                                        </organization>
                                </author>
                                <date year="2024" />
                        </front>
                </reference>
        </references>

        <section title="Wire-format Example" anchor="TLVexample">
            <t>
                The diagram in <xref target="BMP-RM-TLVs"/> shows an example of a
                Route Monitoring message carrying a BGP UPDATE containing 10
                NLRIs. The TLVs are comprised of:
                <list style="numbers">
                    <t>
                        a Group TLV with index 0x000b, pointing to NLRI 1, 2, 3
                        and 10
                    </t>
                    <t>
                        a Group TLV with index 0x000c, pointing to NLRI 4, 5 and
                        6
                    </t>
		    <t>
			a Stateless Parsing TLV with index 0x0000
		    </t>
                    <t>
			a TLV pertaining to NLRI 7
		    </t>
                    <t>
                        a TLV pertaining to the NLRIs listed in the Group TLV
                        defined in 1
                    </t>
                    <t>
                        a TLV pertaining to the NLRIs listed in the Group TLV
                        defined in 2
                    </t>
                </list>
            </t>
            <t>
                <figure anchor="BMP-RM-TLVs" align="center">
                    <artwork align="center">
                        <![CDATA[
   0                   1                   2                   3
   0 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 0 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 0 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 0 1
  +-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+
  |        Common Header + Per-Peer Header (6 + 42 bytes)         ~
  ~                                                               |
  +-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+
  |            type=2            |         length=0x0008       |
  +-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+
  |1|           index=0x000b        |
  +-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+
  |                  value={0x0001,   0x0002,                     |
  |                         0x0003,   0x000a}                     |
  +-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+
  |            type=2            |         length=0x0006       |
  +-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+
  |1|           index=0x000c        |
  +-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+
  |                  value={0x0004,   0x0005,                     |
  |                         0x0006} |
  +-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+
  |            type=4            |         length=0x0005       |
  +-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+
  |0|           index=0             |     cap=69    |	 afi=1	  ~ 
  ~                 |     safi=1    |    value=3    |
  +-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+
  |            type=1            |         length=X            |
  +-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+
  |0|           index=0             |    value=$BGP_UPDATE_PDU{   ~
  +-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+                             ~
  ~                                                               ~
  ~                       NLRI_1 .. NLRI_10                       ~
  ~                                                            }  |
  +-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+
  |            type=SomeTlvX        |         length=0x0004       |
  +-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+
  |1|           index=0x000b        |
  +-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+
  |                          value={4 bytes}                      |
  +-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+
  |            type=SomeTlvY        |         length=0x0008       |
  +-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+
  |1|           index=0x000c        |
  +-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+
  |                          value={8 bytes}                      ~
  ~                                                               |
  +-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+
  |            type=SomeTlvZ        |         length=0x0008       |
  +-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+
  |0|           index=0x0007        |
  +-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+
  |                          value={8 bytes}                      ~
  ~                                                               |
  +-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+
                            ]]>
                    </artwork>
                </figure>
            </t>
        </section>

        <section anchor="Acknowledgements" title="Acknowledgements" numbered="no">
            <t>
		The authors would like to thank Jeff Haas, Camilo Cardona, Thomas Graf,
		Pierre Francois, Ben Maddison, Tim Evens, Luuk Hendriks, Maxence Younsi,
		Ahmed Elhassany, Colin Petrie, Dhananjay Pakti and Shunwan Zhuang for
		their valuable input. The authors would also like to thank Greg Skinner,
		Zongpeng Du and Mohamed Boucadair for their review.
            </t>
        </section>

    </back>
</rfc>
